David A. Hasan

6103 Sun Vista, Austin, TX 78749 (512) 945-3271 david@augerhandle.net
https://augerhandle.github.io/portfolio

I am an aerospace engineer and software developer making a transition to teaching. I have a solid, hands-on understanding of mathematics and physics, years of software development experience, and stories that will help make math real for my students.

Education

• Brigham Young University—Provo, UT

Majoring in Computer Science and in Mathematics

- GPA: 3.77 (overall), 3.77 (CS major), 3.90 (Math major)
- Projected Graduation Date: May, 2006

Experience

• BYU Computer Science Department—Provo, UT

System Programmer: June 2003–present

- Manage 200 Linux and 150 Windows 2000 lab workstations.
- Maintain department Linux servers and document their configuration.
- Develop tools and scripts to improve reliability and functionality of the network.
- Assist users with problems and write tutorials and documentation.
- Argus Systems Group, Inc.—Champaign, IL System Administrator: March, 1997—August, 2000
 - Configured servers, maintained inventory, and managed tape backup system.
 - Prepared all product distribution media (including bootable CDs).

Skills

- **Operating Systems:** Linux (Gentoo, Red Hat, and Debian), Mac OS 9 and X, UNIX (several variants), Windows 98/2000/XP
- Computer Languages:
 - Proficient in C, C++, HTML, Java, LATEX, PHP, UNIX Shells
 - Familiar with Perl, SQL
- Tools and Systems:
 - Proficient in Apache, BIND, CVS/RCS, Make, GnuPG, SSHD, VI
 - Familiar with Kerberos, MySQL, NFS, OpenLDAP, OpenSSL, Postfix, Samba

Achievements and Activities

- Served a voluntary two-year mission in Serbia and Bulgaria (2001–2003). Speak fluent Serbian and basic Bulgarian.
- As a member and president of the BYU Unix Users Group, assist new Linux users and participate in presentations and discussions on advanced topics (2003–present).
- Manage a heterogeneous home network and family server (1996–present).
- Received a National Merit Scholarship.
- Co-authored "Interacting Quantitative Trait Loci Control Phenotypic Variation in Murine Estradiol-Regulated Responses," *Endocrinology* 140 no. 2 (1999).
- Awarded Eagle Scout Rank, Boy Scouts of America (1996).